CARLA JENSEN

Machine Learning Engineer: Improving The Deep Learning Experience With Augmented Algorithms To Increase Program Efficiency By 95%

\$\ +1-605-395-6783 @ help@enhancv.com \(\textit{\omega} \) github.io/waynegomez

Ferney, SD

SUMMARY

Machine Learning (ML) Engineer and Team Leader with 12+ years of experience in managing machine learning lifecycles end-to-end in manufacturing and healthcare. Currently, overseeing the work of 3 ML and Al professionals to constantly find ground for improvement of both supervised and unsupervised learning algorithms - providing 150+ sustainable solutions. Apt at developing, building, and maintaining both ETL and ML pipelines to increase data accuracy and predictability by a 45% AVG. Perfectionist, always open to collaborate with data science and industry professionals to look outside current frameworks and discover 1k+ more working solutions for each individual problem.

EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Engineer and Team Leader **SMART Technologies**

2021 - Present

Ferney, SD

Company, specializing in AI and ML solutions for manufacturing and production.

- Managing the whole ML lifecycle: from end-to-end deployment to constantly updating the systems to reflect new technological innovations and research, provided by 16 nation-wide institutions
- Created 15+ ETL pipeline (to train datasets) and 20+ ML pipelines with Pytorch, skikit-learn, and Numpy (training, assessing, and deploying models)
- Overseeing the work of 3 ML and Al professionals in continuous integrations, testing, deployment on the cloud (Azure Data Factory and ML Pipeline), and release methodologies to achieve 65% more accuracy

Machine Learning Engineer

2018 - 2021

Al and Robotics Ventures

Pittsburgh, PA

Technologies of tomorrow: innovating healthcare solutions across the globe.

- End-to-end deployment of 5 applications: building ML pipelines from scratch (with Python and various learning algorithms) and deploying on the cloud
- Constantly improving the program's efficiency by analyzing individual functions with the help of 3 data engineers
- Uplifted a machine learning project's predictive model precision by 10%
- Testing and experimenting on the platform (running models in parallel and A/B test) to reduce data segmentation and analysis delays by a 13% AVG

ML Researcher: NLP and Speech Recognition

2016 - 2018

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

PhD degree focused in exploring practices improving 5 applications.

- Improved data mining and automation by 45% using a scalable classifier by integrating predictive models and supervised and unsupervised learning algorithms
- Deployed the program across the cloud to meet 100% of all deadlines and follow the highest standard of security measures
- Collaborate with 10+ data engineers to improve the predictability model of data with a focus on patterns and trends

SKILLS

End-to-end deployment ·

Deep Learning · Automation ·

Algorithms • Statistics • Python • C++ •

R · JavaScript · Innovations · APIs ·

Leadership

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Machine Learning

Carnegie Mellon University

2016 - 2018 Pittsburgh, PA

Master of Science in Applied **Data Science**

University of San Diego

2014 - 2016 San Diego, CA

Bachelor of Science in **Applied Computer Science**

University of Nebraska Kearney

2010 - 2014

Kearney, NE

PROJECTS

"Where Should I Eat-Out" Chatbot

2022 - 2022

Ferney, SD

This side-project is a friendly chatbot that makes restaurant recommendations.

Developed own API model, so that the robot successfully analyzes the emotions using APIs - "Where Should I Eat-Out" has answered 100K+ user queries in the past 6 months

Preprocessing CLI For Healthcare Data Processing

2020 - 2021

Pittsburgh, PA

Built simple CLI tool to meet the department's needs and save time in data preprocessing.

The tool was able to convert 10K+ datasets to be 65% more understandable by the algorithm, using Python, OOPS, Panda, and exception handling

